[keys jangling]
[engine starts]
[engine revving]
[Jerry] This is the 1976
Lamborghini Countach LP400,
in Tahiti Blue with a tan interior.
It has a 370 horsepower, four liter,
four cam, 12 cylinder.
The fuel comes through six
twin-throat Webers.
That is good.
And, it could top out
at 180 miles per hour,
which, in 1976...
worked.
I love the short, sharp front end to it.
It's just like a little knife blade
through the air.
The idea of this car, I think,
is you pull up in it,
and you are taking over the scene.
Not unlike my guest today,
the amazingly versatile
and visually spectacular Jim Carrey.
Jim is an unforgettably gifted comedian
and comic actor.
Can you imagine anybody
else even trying to do
Ace Ventura, The Mask,
or Dumb and Dumber? Forget it!
Don't even make the movies.
-[Jim] Yeah?
-[Jerry] Jimmy, it's Jerry.
[Jim] Jerry? [gasps]
What time is it?
[Jerry] Remember, we talked about
going for a cup of coffee.
[Jim] Oh, God, is that today?
Is this today?
[Jerry] Of course today is today!
Today is always today.
[Jim] Yeah, no, no, no.
I'm good. I sleep in my clothes.
I'll be right out.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
[door ringing]
-[Jim grunting]
-[Jerry laughing]
-Doesn't the door work?
-Oh, yeah. It works.
-Whew.
-Is that Don Knotts?
Did you ever think about
the Barney Fife sniff?
[both sniffling]
Oh, yeah.
-Getting ready.
-That was the whole character,
-wasn't it?
-Getting ready to tell you who he is.
[Jim] This is beautiful.
[Jerry] 1976 Lamborghini Countach.
They called it that because
that was what people exclaimed.
When you blow past them in traffic,
"Countach!"
[Jim] Ooh, baby!
Oh, yeah, baby.
Woo-hoo.
It does feel like a Bond movie,
doesn't it?
It's fantastic.
Barney Fife was ego
with nothing to back it up,
and I always think that's the funniest--
-The funniest.
-...kind of character.
And yet, somehow, that confidence
and that arrogance wins in the end.
[Jerry] Who else, for you,
was in a special category?
[Jim] I love David Letterman.
He's big in my life.
It's so funny
because he's such a crank, too.
I think it was the second,
maybe third time I was on,
I hadn't been back there
for quite a while,
maybe two-and-a-half years
or something like that.
During the commercial,
he leaned over to me
after we'd just had the most
incredibly wonderful time together
on camera,
he leaned over to me, and he said,
"So, why haven't you been here
in three years?
Is it me? Is it me?"
And then, "We're back!"
So, I was like, "Yeah..."
And he was just back to being Dave.
-"Is it me?"
"Well, who else could it be?"
Exactly.
It's not Biff.
Did they have air conditioning in '76?
[Jerry] They do. It's on.
But it's kind of like an Alaskan husky
breathing on you.
Okay.
Get me out!
Ah.
[chuckles]
Just knocking on the fourth wall there.
Amazing. It really is real.
Hey, how you doing, man?
You wanna go? You wanna go?
Blow your doors off in this thing.
-[Jim] I had a McLaren for a little while.
-[Jerry] You did?
Yeah. It was too fast for me.
That thing was like [gulps].
And you realize, "What am I eating?"
And it's your testicles.
I'm driving a Tesla. I love the Tesla.
See, I like burning stuff.
We love breathing
what you're burning, baby.
I'm fairly non-localized these days.
So, non-localized means,
it doesn't matter where you are.
-I'm everywhere.
-You're everywhere.
Jerry, you are full of testosterone.
I've been on a cleanse for 21 days.
-Really?
-Yeah.
This is my 21st day of a cleanse.
It's incredible.
Did you just see me climb that gate?
You should have seen me
on the other side, though. I was like...
[grunting]
You were like a dog
trying to get out of a pool.
That'll be you on the 22nd day
of the cleanse, right there.
That's where I'm headed, and I'm about
to go up north to Marin County
and do a silent retreat for five days,
so I won't be speaking during the film.
I don't speak.
You are perfect for that.
You're one of the few guys
who is not handicapped at all...
-No.
-...by not speaking.
[Jerry] I like to remember
people's old bits.
I remember your Henry Fonda
-was one of my favorite bits.
-On Golden Pond.
"Bottom line, huh!"
-"You're a bottom line, man."
"You wanna see my teeth?"
Have you noticed that orange juice
now comes in a variety of pulp?
Like subtle pulp, middle pulp...
You can't take pulp. I need more pulp.
[Jim] You know about the relative
and the absolute, right?
The relative is the things you relate to,
and the absolute is a truth
of consciousness being everything.
So, relating that to the three
different levels of pulp.
No pulp, some pulp...
-There is no pulp.
-...or extra pulp.
There is no pulp no matter how much pulp
they tell you there is.
Pulp is an illusion. There is sensations--
What are those little bits in the juice?
I feel them.
[Jerry] We're in a marina.
This is very refreshing.
[Jim] This is fantastic.
I don't know
how to get out of this, but...
[Jerry chuckles]
Oh, there it is. [whistles]
It slices, it dices, it juliennes fries.
Anybody got some celery, or some...
stuff they need chopped?
[inaudible]
-[vehicle beeping]
-Wait, we should be backing up
while that sound is happening.
[inaudible]
-How you doing, officer?
-Good. How are you?
I'm excellent, man.
[waitress] Huevos rancheros?
That sounds good. Okay, I'll have that.
Sure, kill yourself. It's the Killer Cafe.
So, this is how
I keep life interesting, Jerry.
I bring my own sweetener.
Look, if you do this,
if you go up here,
and then you see how far you can do--
This could be fantastic.
Just estimating now.
I got it. First time.
-Three.
-[Jerry] Oh, my God.
[Jim] Five. Boom.
Thank you.
I used to watch you at the Improv
when I was starting out.
You made me laugh so hard
because I just started
learning to scuba dive.
You did that bit about scuba diving,
and how the whole point of the sport
is not to die.
There's a fish, a rock.
Who cares? Don't die.
♪ I don't wanna die
Don't let me die ♪
Tell me about your stand-up.
You know, first I did impressions.
Lot of people start out with impressions,
but I was obsessed with impressions.
And when I started out,
-I was a Canadian.
-"Was"?
I am, is.
I sent a letter to Carol Burnett
when I was ten years old.
"Dear Carol, I do 120 people.
I would really like
to be a regular on your show,
like Tim Conway and Harvey Korman."
-At ten? That's great.
-Yeah. At ten.
I got a letter back in the mail,
and it was, of course,
one of the assistants, or whatever.
"We wish you the best of luck,
sounds like you're doing great."
I was so in heaven.
I got a letter from Carol Burnett.
And it had Television City crest on it.
I'd struck the big time. I'd made it.
I got a letter from Hollywood.
In Living Color was...
I'm terrible with dates.
I love the fireman.
Yeah, the fire marshal, Bill.
The burn victim fire department guy
was the guy that made us.
When you were really in stand-up days,
what was your set like?
Well, at first, when I decided not to do
the impressions anymore,
I called it performance art,
because it wasn't funny.
But you just cut it, the whole--
Cut it out. In one shot.
And what were you doing then?
I was doing, like, uh,
15 minutes as a cockroach
trying to avoid the vacuum cleaner.
He knows that there's a couple spots
in the living room he can go.
There's the baseboard over there.
Over there, there's something else.
I used to do Jesus,
and if that were me, the Bible
would be a whole different book.
You know, there'd be a scene
where I'm on the cross,
saying, "Wait till my father
hears about this.
You guys are going to get it!"
Kids say "You guys are
going to get it" a lot.
"You guys are going to get it!"
-What is your name?
-Molly.
I'm sorry. I should have asked.
-[Molly] It's okay.
-It's not really who you are, anyway.
I feel like a Molly, though.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
You'll find out different.
Thank you very much, Molly.
Molly, for now.
-Thank you, Molly, for now.
-[Molly giggles]
And I break it down all the time,
philosophically, about comedy.
People come here
to feel good about themselves.
And a laugh is actually
a feeling of superiority to something.
So, there has to be a childlike fun to it.
You can be angry and smarter than us,
but make it fun for us.
I still get caught up in the small me
every once in a while.
Once or twice a day,
I'll get caught up in, like,
"My God, this is...
If that guy doesn't...
How could they do that to the small me?"
Because that's in everybody.
But they don't know it.
They don't know that at the end,
they're going to be so relieved.
Death is going to be
such a welcome freaking moment,
because they've been trying
so freaking hard,
and that's the feeling.
And I can get there sometimes now.
I'm gonna need
one more cup of coffee to get there.
Did you meet Andy Kaufman?
Andy, I knew a little bit.
Like anybody knows Andy.
-Yeah.
-Right?
I love that movie.
[Jim] I mean, honest to God,
that was like a possession.
And once I decided that,
all hell broke loose.
I remember before that movie started,
my friend Nic Cage and me went to dinner.
Nic said, "I gotta go.
Your eyes are different.
I don't know who you are."
It got really uncomfortable.
It's hard to make Nic Cage uncomfortable.
Hard to weird him out.
Hard to weird Nic out.
Thank you so much, Molly.
-No, I insist.
-Thank you.
"I insist." That word really
backs people up, doesn't it?
"You should pay your taxes."
"No, I insist that I do not!"
Do you want to try the Stevia
on the floor?
Yeah, I'll just go for it.
This is fun, Jerry.
[Jerry] Why not?
Why shouldn't we have fun?
It used to be like that with my father.
Rodney Dangerfield
totally fell in love with my dad.
My dad comes to see me.
I introduce him to Rodney.
I'm playing with Rodney, and I get stuck,
and I go like, "Tag team comedy,"
like that, and my dad tags me,
comes in, and starts peppering him.
Rodney's like, "Who the hell is this guy?"
He's laughing hysterically at my dad,
and then started
calling him on his birthday,
and, "How's Percy doing, man?
That guy, man,
he's the funniest guy I ever saw!"
[Jerry] All right.
I'm gonna try as best I can.
I'm gonna go for the record now.
[dramatic music playing]
That's amazing!
You know, it doesn't take much
to feel good about yourself.
There's nothing less than that.
Cheers.
[applauding]
-What are you doing other than this?
-Usually, every weekend, I will go out...
-Yeah? To a big concert?
-...somewhere.
To me, doing stand-up,
it's like being a surfer.
You just paddle out
and you catch some waves.
That's why I paint.
I am in control, I do it, and I'm done.
And I go,
"Something that wasn't there. Fantastic."
[Jim] Next, Le Mans.
I don't even know if Le Mans
exists anymore.
It does, but you don't say it like that.
"Le Mans."
That's French for "The lemons."
Stupid [bleep] makes me laugh.
-Why is that?
-It's not stupid.
So, you're going to show me
the studio today?
[Jim] Yeah, man. Sure.
-Oh, great.
-It's my heart.
I love this place.
[Jerry] Wow.
[Jim] Come on in.
-Thank you so much for showing me this.
-Yeah.
-Well, you're the only one who's seen it.
-I love this.
This is the womb for me.
And I just love paint.
I love the colors,
I love everything about it.
-The gorilla with the machine gun.
-Yeah, the gorilla with the machine gun.
I got power, now.
-Are these canvases?
-Yeah, those are canvases.
Getting big.
Well, if you build it, they will come.
[Jerry] Field of Dreams.
I love that movie.
At the end--
You sob. There's no way not to sob.
There's no way you can't.
That simple thing of like,
"Let's have a catch.
-Spend your time with me for a second."
-Mmm-hmm.
-Is so...
-Right!
...insanely ingrained in us.
That is a great description of why
that moment's so powerful.
Just a moment with me.
-Yeah.
-Just give me a moment.
That's that whole movie,
it comes down to that.
[inaudible]
[Jim] I could disappear
from show business forever,
and feel wonderful about what I've done,
what I've experienced,
what I've been given,
but I am always grateful
that wherever I go, somehow,
I did something
that makes people brighten.
And that is a wonderful thing somehow.
That was awesome.
-I need a hug from you.
-[woman] Oh.
-[Jim] Oh, yeah!
-You're my favorite.
I could get addicted to this.
It's so good.
I gotta share it. Hold it.
I'm gonna need to let some things out.
Just give it here. Give it to me.
-It was awesome. Did it feel good?
-You are so sexy.
-[all laugh]
-[both] Mmm!